Rahul Nair

Developer @ Apple

Summary

I use technology to build innovative solutions to challenging problems. My experience runs the gamut from social search and mobile apps, all the way to packaged enterprise software. With 25+ patents and 15+ publications, I am always ready to explore new areas.

Experience

Developer at Apple

January 2017 - Present

Blog Editor at Golden Gate Lotus Club

2008 - Present

Editor of the Chapman Report Online (http://gglotus.org/blog/) - the official blog of the Golden Gate Lotus Club. I also run the club Facebook page which has 1200+ likes.

Staff Engineer at Delphix

August 2014 - November 2016 (2 years 3 months)

I lead a team that reported directly to the CTO and developed support for new data platforms within the core Delphix product. Support for IBM DB2 was our first GA product release and was successfully deployed at multiple customer sites. We also developed alpha releases for SAP HANA and MongoDB.

Additionally I ran the Delphix internal hackathon program which created multiple internal tools and customer facing product features.

Senior Software Developer at THRED

June 2013 - July 2014 (1 year 1 month)

Thred was a mobile app/game founded by game industry legend Will Wright and included a team that had previously created genre-defining works like SimCity, The Sims, Spore, Google Earth and Carmen San Diego.

I designed and built the internal location platform that integrated data from multiple geo sources (Flickr, Foursquare, Instagram, Facebook, Twitter, etc...) into a single source of truth. I also created our initial mobile prototypes and wrote activity detection algorithms to determine a users location and probable activities throughout the day.

Senior Software Development Engineer at Microsoft

January 2011 - April 2013 (2 years 3 months)

Member of Early Stage Product Group within the Online Services Division. Prototyped and developed new concepts within Bing Search with a focus on Personalization, Social and Strategy.

Ideated, iteratively prototyped and internally evangelized the concepts that became Bing Linked Pages as well as the "Friends who might Know" feature of the Social Sidebar. Other project details are currently confidential

Research Engineer at Yahoo!

May 2005 - December 2010 (5 years 7 months)

In general my work focused on social, mobile, front page and advertising.

From 2009-2010 I was part of a prototyping team that worked on a variety of products including front page, social advertising, mobile and Connected TV.

From 2008-2009 I was a member of the Early Stage Product group in Yahoo! Connected Life (Mobile). Primary focus was on location, mobile and media with an emphasis on developing new methods to infer the content and context surrounding media.

From 2005-2008 I was a member of Yahoo! Research Berkeley and my public projects from that time include ZoneTag, Zurfer, TagMaps and FireEagle. Single-handedly designed and built the cell tower based positioning platform that served as the backend for Yahoo! Mobile location services for over two years.

Researcher at UC Berkeley

April 2005 - May 2005 (1 month)

Worked with Prof. Marc Davis on conducting research into collecting metadata information from camera phone users. Responsibilities include technical feasibility studies, cell phone programming, UI design, user testing, data mining, etc...

Graduate Research Assistant at Georgia Institute of Technology

2002 - 2004 (2 years)

Lead investigator with Dr. Elizabeth Mynatt to study task management strategies of knowledge workers. Responsibilities included protocol design, user research, iterative UI design, human subject testing and data analysis. Engineering tasks included writing window tracking software, using Visual Basic for Applications (VBA) to track activity in the Microsoft Office suite, instrumenting email clients to log activity and building adaptive software to detect task changes.

Research Intern at Ricoh Innovations Inc

May 2003 - August 2003 (3 months)

Lead designer in creating a multi-user, collaborative book marking system to create augmented recordings of meetings and presentations for later review and/or quick skimming. Duties included background research,

iterative design, building prototypes and final evaluation. Technologies used include SMIL, SVG and the Batik toolkit and were integrated using Visual Basic and Java.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

MS, Human Computer Interaction, 2002 - 2004

University of Madras

B.E, Computer Science & Engineering, 1998 - 2002

Honors and Awards

Hackathon Audience Choice Winner, Hackathon Winner, Though Leadership Award, Hack Day Winner, Vannevar Bush Best Paper Award

Rahul Nair

Developer @ Apple



Contact Rahul on LinkedIn